coming up on today's episode the funny
dirty little secret of data in the AI
world is we all the exact same access to
data all of them still have a lot of
ways to go jumping from AI assistant to
the developer to an autonomous Junior
developer and this is like this Holy
Grail category none of these things are
junior developers at this point you
still need a developer to Hands-On
keyboard we're in a Dev Le AI assisted
world the developer is still front and
center hands- on keyboard asking
questions or getting some feedback
whether it be assistant or asking in a
side by-side chat kind of world it's
assisting the developer to a degree a
misplaced comma and code is incredibly
bad it like changes the functionality
but misplaced comma and language can be
bad but for the most part humans who
read these things can Overlook that but
the compiler can't Overlook that I wish
I was not 45 years old I wish I was 20
again or 50 because this is a completely
different next 25 years of my career we
have a belief and our belief is that in
an infinite World the general purpose
model is the way to go toward to get to
AGI but we don't live in an unbounded
world we have a lot of constraints so my
belief and pool siiz belief would be
that the focus yields higher results
better
results you're listening to the AI
native Dev brought to you by Tesla
[Music]
hello everyone welcome back to the AI
native Dev today I am going to have a
really fun conversation with Jason
Warner Jason and I go a fair bit back
Jason and I was eight years it's always
how yeah eight years all these numbers
get a little bit big probably biggest
relevant claim to fame over here is he
was github's CTO at the time that built
that you built up co-pilot and actions
and a bunch of other fun things over
there before that was you were the GM at
Heroku right building up a lot of end to
end developer workflows canonical if
before that and then now you are after a
stint on the dark side at Red Point
Ventures you are running poolside you
founded and running poolside which is a
code focused Foundation model does that
sound right did I miss anything anything
Key here no you got it you tore through
my background which was yeah invested
for a couple of years but GitHub Heroku
and canonical basically means that I'm
pretty useless if it's got a motor but
useful if it's got a keyboard that's
easy understand what I do and now we're
building poolside which is it's a
frontier AI company so think open AI
anthropic Etc focused on software as a
as the domain and the disciplin and so
Focus for as developers we're building
the state-of-the-art language models for
software development specifically and
there's a host of things that means but
that's what we do yeah and we'll dig
into a bunch of those so thanks for
coming on to to the show Jason and so
Jason maybe start by helping us level
set a bit on the foundations of this
thing we're going to talk a lot about
codenation and the you know doing so
with llms or these Foundation models can
I ask you to just ground us a little bit
about like why does this thing even work
like what are sort of the fundamentals
of Co generations with llm and why is it
different now I think the the best way
to describe this how I to try to
describe this to folks who are not in
the field which is just that the
let me take a step back and and say
something that maybe we don't typically
do which is we owe open AI DBT of
gratitude from a commercialization from
a corporation perspective they went and
they did a lot of hard work for a bunch
of years and when it wasn't really
invogue to do it and they proved out a
bunch of things and one of the things
that they really proved out is that um
all the scaling laws are going to hold
all of the various things that we
culated about as in industry or in
academics might be true they said we
true and they just had the guts to go do
it and throw whole bunch of money at it
right and effectively what we've seen is
that as the as these models get larger
we throw more data at it and more
compute at it what they're able to do is
effectively solve more complex problems
and solving is a air quote thing that
we're going to have to get into in a bit
just think of these things as
understanding enough from their internal
systems to be able to answer questions
and that's the way I look at this is
like hey you asked a question it has got
a whole bunch of Representative State
inside of its inside of it its networ
networ and knows how to navigate that
and you'll hear a lot of us in the
industry and you've seen this yourself
just say we don't necessarily know how
these things work but no we know how
they work it's all math um what what we
can't say is exactly what the answer is
going to be every time that is just a
thing that we can't do because what
they're effectively doing is they're
saying based upon the probabilistic XYZ
I'm going to answer it this way this
time yeah more more that we understand
how do we educate them yes but we don't
necessarily know precisely learn and
what is it that they would distill from
every yeah how do we nudge these things
into a way that is acceptable to us as
humans to engage with them yeah and
another sort of basic question is
cenation in the early conversations
there was a lot of conversation about
how do the llms even find out about code
and the premise was that the initial
learning was on comments and text that
revolved around that code but that
subsequently the state-of-the-art has
improved and some sort of dedicated code
specific
content was
created is that correct can you tell us
maybe a couple words about that
Evolution there's some history here
which is you end up in the early days
you ended up with code specific models
and actually there's a whole host of
people who are still building code
specific models models who are trained
exclusively on source code itself and
then you have the open Ai and anthropics
who are general purpose who have code in
their training data and then you have us
who are domain specific or focusing on
software so we have slightly different
orientations but what we saw ear what
open AI say we as an industry as the
global we as an industry but open
specifically saw and a bunch of the
academics saw was if you take a general
purpose model which is all NLP data and
you say hey we're going to just take all
the NL data but all of a sudden you
start adding code to it it gets smarter
and by smarter it means it's reasoning
and its logic and all that sort of stuff
starts to improve then there was a whole
bunch of research onto why that is and
then a whole bunch of us who are more
pragmatic just said that's effing cool
we don't actually care about the Y in
that specific case but holy crap adding
code to the can do some amazing things
yeah you can do some amazing things and
that's effectively where open AI
anthropic and a bunch of general purpose
models are is like okay we're going to
add code to this because it's going to
make the general reasoning capabilities
of the models better and then but a side
effect of that is that it's going to be
able to answer code questions as well
now it's going to be limited in
understanding of software but it's going
to be very good at code in the moment
and then the code specific ones like the
the small language models code only
models are really good at things like
ghost writing or code completion because
what they're effectively doing is this
my wording here and this is where
co-pilot started as well is fancy code
completion is like looking at the next
the line that you're trying to write and
going to complete the last little bit of
it what are the next tokens in that it's
just next token prediction again but at
a different level a different type of
thing and then the function level Etc
and then what is happening in coolside
is representative of this and there's
others doing this as well is that you're
flipping it around and say okay so why
don't we focus on software as the domain
and then what can we do by to advance
the stateof the art and that that way
similar to what's going to happen or has
is happening right now in robotics or is
going to happen in drug Discovery and
you'll have domain specific ones who
folks who are saying I'm going to go
solve this problem specifically so it
applies the same techniques and maybe
the same learnings that we had around
scaling and maybe even a little bit of
the combination of the text around the
code or going from codes to software
that maybe the original the original AI
models on it oftentimes are quite
dismissive of anything that was uh that
was outside the the code itself so even
taking advantage of our human
understanding as we would as developers
to better understand the code itself but
if before it was like a lot of text a
lot of text add some code to that text
understand everything together and then
maybe start removing the text and focus
more and more on the code but with maybe
some of the practices I guess would you
say we anchor Today more in a
focused generic model that we have
refined and then from here now we're
augmenting or does it more resemble the
AI models of the past augmented with
withm I think if you're asking about the
general purpose models that exist today
like Claws and the gbd4 and things of
that nature what I what they do in my
opinion is is you they're really good at
language and they're applying similar
techniques to the code side of the fence
and the result of that is that they
understand what how to answer questions
relative to code now on the inner
workings of I'm not as familiar with the
inner workings of gp4s or the claws and
exactly how they're applying those
techniques but I know from us what we do
is we actually have if you think about
our our neur Network that we're building
at poolside we actually have slightly
different techniques you you treat a
code data set an L data set slightly
different and the interleaved portions
of those involve understanding what is
which like a comment is treated in one
way but it's got to have context it's
relative to the context of the code and
the code is relative to the context of
the comment so it has to be able to
understand both but you're going to
apply slightly different learning
techniques to to those because they they
require slightly different learning
techniques yeah yeah and that makes
sense there's a whole world of knowledge
that is not anchored in language but
rather anchored in code we code is super
fascinating because a comma a misplaced
comma in code is incredibly bad it like
changes the work not work functionality
but it misplace comma and language can
be bad but for the most part human who
read these things can Overlook that but
the compiler can't Overlook that it's a
very different notion instrumentation
the Telemetry the the understanding of
whether something was or was not correct
and the context of code is there's a lot
more opportunity there versus maybe in
language in which oftentimes
implications and whether you got it
right or not are a lot harder to deduce
yeah we can get into this one later yeah
absolutely so before we dig we're going
to unravel some of these different types
and strands on it so still a little bit
on the level set let's talk a little bit
about what is the current
state-ofthe-art so I'm curious you dig
into it you have your own one of the
sort of top models in the code side how
what is the most impressed that you've
been from code generation if you think
about examples you've recently seen or
maybe edge cases in in how you challenge
your own models and models around I
think there's a couple of that always
impressed me whether it be what we're
building or what somebody else has built
as well but these two that kind of
always stand out is somebody who doesn't
know anything about software but they
want to solve a problem and for and and
they've they're able to go from a
nothing to a something that is just a
monumentally impressive thing and
whenever you can think about with
experience how long that might have
taken somebody typically and the
reduction of cycles and time saving they
have in there that's just a really
impressive thing you can see this all
the time on Twitter these days people
say I I use x to go build this thing in
some amount of hours and they couldn't
fathom themselves doing this that's just
impressive now the other one and my joke
here is anytime I ask any model about
ffmpeg and it actually gives me a usable
real answer that works at the command
line I'm always impressed because FFM
Peg is a effing nightmare yeah so many
flags there so many flags and it's it's
just one of those ridiculous things it's
not nothing's turned complete until it
can answer F questions but the one that
really impresses me is when and if you
think about how I'm answering this
question I'm talking about novice
developer I'm talking about experience
developer so in an experienc developer
all of a sudden you get some sort of
weird error message popped up from a
thing that blew up and you just like cut
paste that thing into it or you ask it
to say what is this and it actually
knows it can give you the solution to
that problem it can point you to the
thing and I remember like my own
experience for the first time I saw this
was with gpt3 when it was doing a
certain thing when we were building
co-pilot we were navigating this and I
pped in some sort of log that we had was
like it showed me not in the code but it
showed me like where to think about the
problem happening and it wasn't super
obvious I didn't spend a lot of time
with it the error message but I was like
oh wow that was actually correct and
then recently when I was doing with what
we're building um something blew up and
I piped in the error message and it
literally pointed at the piece of code
it said this is where this is broken
this whole thing and it was a long long
like very kind of complex hard to
error message and I was like oh I wish I
was not 45 years old I wish I was 20
again or 15
again because this is a completely
different next 25 years of my career
yeah and I think we didn't really
properly introduce these terms but how
much do you think this is retrieval
versus reasoning so how much of these
types of examples are really around
sparing someone the need to do something
that would have been repetitive versus
some sort of deep understanding that has
been uh embedded somewhere between
within those neural networks to help
some reach conclusions super hard to
answer right this is one of those you're
asking me almost a got feel on that's
true yeah yeah and so how I'm answering
this is going to be maybe dissatisfying
to folks but I would say a lot of this
is obviously going to be retrieval this
is going to be it understands and scen
is whatever but there's obviously cases
where it could not have possibly have
seen enough data on that thing to be
able to answer it and my my answer to
this is I always ask questions in Niche
programming languages to pool side I ask
about Crystal I ask about Pony I ask
about these weird languages that a lot
of people don't know about but you can
see it having kind of intelligence
around problems and this is where it
gets interesting it's like the problem
that you're trying to solve is X so the
specific implementation in this syntax
the language would be y that first part
is actually going to be what we might
classically call intelligence it
understands the problem and understands
how to solve that problem and it's
applying it to this that's what we as
humans would do and so that is super
impressive that said we are we have the
ramp that we have is ridiculous like
where people think we are in the moment
is wherever you think of it is we're at
the lower end of that curve what we're
going to see in the next five to 10
years is going to be ridiculous yeah
it's going to be dramatic yeah but I
love that example because indeed when
you're when you evolve in your career
and your skills as a software developer
you become much more naturally polyglot
like you understand the concepts of it
at the beginning you're a lot more I use
this type of polyfill or whatever in
JavaScript I use these classes I use
this in the SDK you are indeed more
retrieval you're just sort of repeating
a pattern you might have learned or you
sit down and you think deeply over time
you build intuition that intuition is
oftentimes transcends language it's it's
about concepts of understanding how the
systems work and so I love the esoteric
programming language example because it
almost proves out the polyglot nature of
the model and you can ask it it's always
interesting to me because I think you
can ask a question you could do two
things like whenever you're evaluating
these things the more experienced people
versus less experienced and like naive
approach to evaluating these things like
people might grab a random llm off the
the streets and say I'm going to go
against human eval I'm going to go
against all these other things a lot of
that stuff is just one it's it's BS
because people train on the data now
that's just not a thing that you should
yeah of course once you set a benchmark
and it's public that's the
it but the other is ask it to do things
that would be to apply Concepts and this
is again like in if I were to do X in y
how would I do it and again it has to
understand X and it has to understand
what it would mean to do it in y and
those two things are the interesting
bits so you were to say I want to go do
X in Rex or I want to go do X in cobal a
Fortran and then I want to go do X in
Java or Pearl python so completely
different and and hasc or whatever it is
that you have to understand that it's
it's a applying two different things
here it's not just saying this is how
you do X in Rust it has to understand
the both sides of that fence to be a to
yeah super interesting so indeed maybe
be like before we dig into indeed the
all sorts of the forks and the road of
this of this domain what would you say
is currently the boundaries of of the
llms today and and maybe which ones are
a little bit surprising I think it's
easy enough to just imagine something
that is massively complex but what would
you say are the things that today's
state-ofthe-art Coen llms yourselves
included can't yet get over so I think
that let's just um Baseline where I
think we are which is all of these
things are great code assistance so in
my words what I say is we're in a Dev Le
AI assisted world the developer is still
front and center hands on keyboard
asking questions or getting some
feedback whether it be code assistants
in terms of like ghost writing and code
completion or asking in a side by-side
chat kind of world but it's a assisting
the developer to a degree and yes it
might be writing lines of code and they
have to accept it or whatever it be but
it's still assisting the developers and
I think it does well like the top tier
thing I think all of these things do
well is they do more they do better
explaining so if you think about like 10
out of 10 and nine out of 10 and eight
out of 10 it's in the upper tier
explaining so if you have a a file or a
repo or whatever what does this do it's
really good at that highlighting code
explain this to me that sort of thing or
just asking generic questions like in
Java if I weren't wanted to do this how
would I do it explain how I would do
that it's very good at that teered down
from that is actually the the generation
of the code I think it's not as good at
generating code that none of them are
even though they're if you look at them
objectively that's still a strong
function but if you have to tier them
that's that now where I think that all
of them still have a lot of ways to go
is jumping from AI assistant to the
developer to an autonomous Junior
developer and this is like this Holy
Grail kind of category where we keep on
saying these things are junior
developers at this point that's not true
none of these things are junior
developers at this point you still need
a developer the Hands-On keyboard and I
think that what we've been trying to do
is work around the model limitations by
putting agents around them and all that
sort of stuff but we've done this
multiple times with gpt2 gpt3 gp4 and
eventually the models themselves become
so much more capable that the agents
themselves will fall away as well um
because the capabilities will be
inherent in the models so where I think
that we do not have these uh strong
capabilities is on the quote unquote
model agency side of the fence which is
why we're building a lot of those tools
so they're not going to work
autonomously you could tool them to work
semi-autonomously if you want but
there's limitations in that is that a is
that primarily a reliability problem is
it because if they're a useful assistant
if they're an assistant that keeps
getting it wrong they're also useless
yeah if they get it right often enough I
think the Delta between autonomy and an
assistant at least one dimension of it
is is the notion of reliability How
likely is it to get it right but this is
like in like gut here at the moment
which is that let's just call it like a
degrading graph at some point if you
start to talk to G gp4 and any generic
model about software as an example and
you ask it to continue to get more and
more specific as it goes the answers
actually will decrease over time because
they get the broader and broader context
there's too much stuff being pulled in
which is why so many people go after
context so imagine you want to go after
a very difficult problem and you need to
keep going back and forth and keep
putting more and more uh information
into this your answers are going to get
less precise and it feels like it's
going to actually degrade in in time now
again I'm saying feel here because again
this is I'm using these things it's very
hard to measure these things as well as
we pointed out the benchmarks are a way
to do it but they are they're useful in
some fashion it's still a measuring
stick but there clearly only one lens
yeah there's also ways around even what
I'm talking about here because you can
start saying to you're going to brought
in the context window this you're going
to stuff everything that you wanted from
the previous into this and see what it
can do and if the model has been trained
to understand that you can it could get
some degree of confidence out of that or
you can say hey we're g to start doing
embeddings and we're start doing all the
stuff around the model itself but more
how I think about this is people always
want that ask the question will software
developers exist because they view a
world where somebody's going to ask a
singular question create me a Twitter
clone and then out pops Twitter clone
and that is a holy Grail type of
scenario that I do think exists in the
future but we're not there today because
what happens in between there here and
there is so much Plumbing of that system
that's going to be required to go do
that so it's not just the AI system
anymore it's like everything around it
now I think interestingly I think the AI
will actually get to that point that's
what I all of us who are building models
I think believe and but we're just not
there at all so let's let's maybe start
bifa some of the different types first
let's dig a little bit into this notion
of a generic versus a code specific
model so we touched a bit on that
already in saying types of sources but
still I don't know if you can how would
you draw the line between a generic open
AI GPT type model versus a code focused
model like psite so I think the way to
answer this question the way I've tried
to answer this question is what I
believe happens in the world and so let
me take a core belief I think all of us
have so let's just take anthropic open
AI pool side because the two leading
general purpose models the first the
domain specific for software as an
example so why didn't we go build a
general purpose model and then start try
say hey we're going to Market it towards
the software side of the fence we have a
belief and our belief is that in an
infinite World so infinite compute
Infinite Energy infinite data infinite
all of us at the same time the general
purpose model is the way to go toward to
get to AGI because like we all are doing
the exact same thing we're trying to use
use as much compute throw as much data
at this thing had it learn as fast as
possible Etc grow as large as possible
as smart as possible as dense as
possible we've already learned some of
these learnings into chpt was that at
least to a substantial degree these
scaling laws have worked give it more
data give it more compute it produces
better results yes so we I think we
would all say that we believe the same
thing so in that in that infinite or
unbounded World we'd all be doing the
same thing but we don't live in an
unbounded world we have a lot
constraints so we have constraints on
energy we have constraints on how many
chips you can Network at the moment even
in the future how much data we have in
the world and then how we're going to
spend our time to focus these things and
now so my belief and pool siiz beliefs
and others who are going to build like
robotic specific ones or drug Discovery
specific ones would be that the focus
yields higher results better results and
so the bation here is that the we're
going to focus our compute efforts we're
going to focus our data efforts we're
going to focus XY fine tuning efforts to
be around the domain and then we're
going to say good example here is that
pools side's it's a actually very good
general purpose model you ask a
butterfly questions or to write a song
or a poem it does it but it's not our
Focus we don't care we're not going to
Market it towards it and we're not going
to really fine tune it that way we're
going to spend all of our energy and
efforts this way so the bifurcation is
really going to be about Focus how we
think about what we're going to care
about how we're going to care about our
data sets what we're going to craft the
human responses for how we're going to
think about the users interacting with a
system and that's just not a first
decision and it is it should very much
be a first decision but it's also a
pragmatic KnockOn decision for even we
don't care that it regresses on
butterfly Anatomy when we start to add a
ton of synthetic data to this we just
don't it's got to be good enough it
doesn't have to be excellent at that
yeah because at some point more
data can translate into more distraction
above and beyond there there's the
fundamental just like sheer dollars
computes like how much do you fun into
it there's also the element of of focus
if you give it more information it has
to factor in more things it's harder and
so good example here is our distribution
we're 5050 so we're 50 NL data and 50%
code data so if you just think about
from the data distribution perspective
what it is and if you think about all
llms that's just distribution over their
data so the more that they know about
non software the more they know about
that but the more they know about
software the more they know about
software the more iations they can make
and think about our our fine-tuning data
sets as an example and obviously we've
become known for the what we call
reinforcement learning via code
execution feedback which is effectively
building a massive simulator environment
to generate ton of synthetic data that
augments our models and this allows us
to get out of the conundrum of not
having enough data in the world we're
actually generating our way out of not
having enough data but that's a bunch of
our secret saww but it's also the focus
on the domain matters here because
that's such a large effort that I would
say that nearly half of our engineering
half of our entire team is focused on
that one problem it's not it's a problem
that you would only really tackle if you
cared deeply about software as your
Prime use case yeah and and this is it
is very interesting and it's I think the
maybe like a p maybe a perspective here
is that code if you want to understand
it is not just the words around it it's
not just the static analysis of it it's
also observing that code in production
so your learning your ability to
understand correctness from
incorrectness track the journey I
remember you and I have had
conversations back when you were at
GitHub about GitHub Futures and where
you would it Go and even back then of
course your Heroku roots and all that
you always were passionate about closing
the loop between the code and the and
the execution of it but it really Builds
on that perception that there's unique
Insight or like very powerful Insight
that you can achieve from observing code
there's a host of things so there's this
one magical workflow I made the joke
earlier that I'm useless around engines
and that sort of thing but there's one
workflow that I always think about and
have been thinking about for the past 15
years and it's essentially every time a
developer touches a key on their
keyboard to what happens in Productions
that whole Magic contic chain in between
touching the single key all the way to
something happening in production and if
you think about what the most perfect
system for developer would be was if you
even touch a single key production
changes and update dates and all of the
different safeguards and all the things
that were we should be in place would be
in place now that's not a thing that you
we can do you can't theoretically
collapse the entire sdlc down to that
single magical workflow but you can
think about it that way and they all
matter there's a whole bunch of things
that matter the keyboard down here
matters what's happening in production
matters observing what's happening with
the software matters seeing what how the
software changes as an example so even
if we're talking about AI systems not
just looking at the code but seeing how
code has changed even historically as
you're training these things or in the
future understanding what is happening
here so you can actually answer certain
questions all of that stuff matters and
so again this is why we're focused on
the domain so and I get very obsessed
over two things here so one is the
developer experience not just answer
being intelligent answering the
questions but also if we have that
kinetic chain what can we do for
developers in the future how can we make
things better faster simpler smooth all
of the rough edges around the
industry and I think I think all this
unique data is you know sounds like it
can be very very powerful and I guess
you're sort of seeing it and literally
kind of betting betting the company on
it but you know I can absolutely see how
that gives you insights that really make
you better but I think your your case is
twofold one is that there is unique data
that if you were to bother and invest
the time and Ingenuity and all of that
in in achieving and producing this data
of times then you can actually make your
models a lot better at getting a better
developer experience but also at just
producing better results producing
better software uh on it the second is
that even if a generic model was to
bother which is a big if because they
have a lot of other fish to fry but even
if they were to bother and invest in
building all that time the fact that
would represent a smaller percentage of
their total data of their total neural
network and things that the model has to
factor in would lead them to produce
inferior results the first one 100%
absolutely and it's something we've
proven out it's the basis for what we've
done our most recent fund raise on we've
got all the data on that yes the second
one requires a little bit of context but
the answer is yes given the choice
between two roughly equivalent let's
call them like decently close to each
other types of things somebody who's
focused on a set of things and been over
here on the software side of the fence
always going to produce better results
that said if we're talking about Epoch
differences if we're talking about the
difference between a gpt2 and a g GPT 5
it's very difficult to make up a gap
between a gpt2 with specific orientation
to a gp5 general purpose so it's this is
open ai's entire thesis which is we
don't care about anything else except
for scale that is the only thing that we
care about so if I were to say answer
that question by saying the only thing
that matters is the fact that I'm
focused I would be dead wrong because I
too have to keep up by increasing my
core models reasoning capabilities by
increasing its neural network size and
all of the different things that other
people have gone through and it's the
focus that gives me the also the other
advantages if again let's just take up
to the future if I am roughly or any
model is roughly gpt2
sized very unlikely that no matter how
much time and energy and effort they
focus they' be anywhere even close to a
GPT 5 will be y it does require people
need to be in the ballpark you still
need the of caliber to be able to
produce those and I guess how does that
play out in models for instance like
llama and we've seen a variety of others
recently especially in the open source
side although you see this in in the
hosted one as well which is you have
llama and you have code llama and I
guess my external perspective is
probably a decent chunk of that is it's
take the code related subset of data and
just run the training separately so in
their case maybe they didn't give the
level of investment and focus on the
custom and unique data that you have but
they did avoid distractions by training
a model separately maybe on code is that
am I understanding it correctly it's a
little bit more nuanced than that just
think of it as llama and code llama are
like similar families of things this is
more of an orientation so it the size
won't be there I would not expect that
anybody that meta where the rumor is
that they're going to release a four and
a five billion parameter llama 3 here
soon something like that general purpose
llama 3 they'll have a code llama
variant of that that and it'll just be
some sort of it'll be a smaller one so
that people can use it in various
different ways it's probably if I were
to think about internal to what they've
done it's probably some either
distillation of that to to be smaller
and more focused or some maybe earlier
techpoint or something like that that
they then said okay from this checkpoint
what we're going to do is we're just
going to apply more focused code data of
some sort but I honestly don't fully
understand exactly what they're doing
internally to this but what I can say is
use an analogy here I I think is is
useful which people because I think
people get very confused about yeah code
specific software specific general
purpose and I just like to say the
following typically which is let's say
you're an athlete and you're early in
your career you're young or whatever
there's always the the focus saying
don't specify your athletic career too
early just be a general purpose athlete
just be very good just be very good at
what you do but at some point if you
want to be the best in the world you're
going to have to say basketball's my
sport or golf is my sport because
they're very different and they require
a base level athleticism to a degree in
each one but they're different and you
can focus on them giv your own skill set
I think what the entire industry needs
to wrap its head around is that applies
here too that you because we don't live
in an infinite unbounded World we do
have to say hey this is the thing that
we're naturally going to be excellent at
or best at and then these other things
we might still be good you put LeBron
James who's the best in the world
basketball player player on a pickle
ball court as an example he's his base
level of athleticism is going to beat a
lot of people in the world yeah but
there's going to be pickle ball specific
people who are going to beat LeBron
James who they would never have the same
level of athleticism to him to a degree
so it's a weird thing for us to wrap our
head around because we just assume that
one system should solve all these things
it's never going to be the case yeah no
understood and and it sounds like there
was a decent amount of overlap to your
gpt2 versus GPT 5 analogy there is
significant state of the art that you
still need to keep up with you still
need to do a great job at but then the
subsequent uh Focus helps you both in
terms of the creativity of the time
investment of where the novel stuff
happens but also just the fundamental
how do you focus the system because you
only care about this one thing which
makes a lot of sense so maybe let's talk
about another version of it which is
training on customer code and we talked
a little bit talked about the difference
between maybe t
on uh customer code context maybe on the
other side actual straight out some
training runs that run on it maybe for
starters tell us a little bit what does
it mean to to tune or train on customer
codes just make sure we refer to the
same thing yeah the way that I uh refer
to this is basically that uh you're
you're going to want to add their
customers confusing term here but I
always say customer context to the
system because you you want the
customers's information to be available
to the models whether it be baked into
the model or around the model and the
reason why I think that's important I
find that vital is because it as a
programmer you can think about this as
one way I have a tool and then I have a
whole bunch of documentation around it
so if the tool is abstract from all the
documentation or all the other systems
like there's a bridge that needs to be
built between those that's all
effectively you're think about doing is
hey I'm going to build that bridge and
whether or not you bake it into the
model or you bake it around the model or
how you think about it but it's
important that you not ignore that
because if you ignore it it's an
abstract tool it's just a tool that you
can apply and then you have to apply to
your context yep yep so you want to sort
of build that in and I think that makes
a lot of sense for to me even just the
notion of knowing which apis exist and
what are some of the uh best practices I
think it's more important in software by
the way than it is in a lot of other
domains where I think it's also
important but it it's more important to
know what they do as an example hey at X
Corporation we use these libraries or
this is our standard or this is our
entire approach to sdlc or our entire
approach to deployments or here's how
configuration files look or feel or all
that sort of stuff and we all know how
it is you walk into a corporation day
one you're like how do we do things here
yeah I think that's probably the best
analogy is if you come along as a even a
very capable developer you come in day
one you can just write some code you
want to look at some code around you to
understand uh and project to project is
different because Legacy projects or
even modern projects have different
standards and stuff like that becomes
like Nightmare and if you just go off
like a a bull in a china shop and and do
things your way that that would be
frowned upon and and it wouldn't be very
collaborative you wouldn't be able
wouldn't be able to work with others
terribly well but I wonder how much is
that knowledge significant for the
actual model operation so how much is it
hey look at my code or look at my
Project's codee and or my organization's
code whatever it is and summarize out of
it the whatever my Norms some
distilled
2100 page summary of the this is how we
write code in this organization and then
almost introduce that into the context
versus how much is it an actual deep
understanding of the systems themselves
that is embedded in the code right when
you look at the code you see everybody
avoiding a certain service right you're
seeing everybody applying a certain
pattern to I don't know scaling right or
how do you shed loads so I guess how
much is it generic distilling maybe even
human interpretable and
reviewable information about this is our
best practices versus needing to be
actually attached to the sub sometimes
substantial amounts of code that exist
in the Enterprise so let's take a second
to to BU for two things so one is in as
the world sees what pool slide is
building this will make sense too but I
always quantify things into two
different modes and it's easiest to
visualize it this way is are you asking
a web page a question or are you asking
are you interacting with these AI
systems in your IDE and there's two
different kind of modes that you would
expect reasonably to have inside now we
at cool side have embeded this in in all
the different context you can do this
but imagine you're on the web page
you're just saying hey how would I do
this or I'm trying to do this what would
happen here mhm and in that case what's
useful is the explaining or the giving
some sort of an answer and going back
and forth and all that so imagine that
you're working inside an Enterprise and
you say how do we do deployments here or
how do we do AWS deployments or gcp
deployments explain that to me it's a
really good back and forth it's an
Internal Documentation system or okay so
on the Bedrock project that we were
working on together or the Bedrock
project how do we do this and compare
that to the substrate project that sort
of thing that is incredibly useful in in
a way that becomes specific to to the
the context of the customer but it has
nothing to do with the code per se it
has to do with the standards and what
they've done and all that but the
context matters so the code Nam but
naturally it would needs to be able to
look at things broadly it would need to
see all of project a and all of Project
B to be able to contrast it above and
beyond how do you make those
associations how does understand how to
do that that's why it's different than
just fine-tuning and Rag and all that
sort of stuff by baking into the model
it matters there because the
associations matter the context from
what it knows generically to the
specific context matter because it's
making those associations and it's
ability to discern and understand and
reason about it now on the code side of
the fence it it's I think it's even more
obvious which is as an example like this
is how we guard against buffer overflows
here that sort of thing you can see it
as it sees more of a customer's code
specific data in that instance here it's
going to say oh this is I've never seen
this style before I have seen this style
but I'm seeing it all the time now and
so that's what they do that's what this
customer does in this orientation and
now that is before we even getting
feedback loops so good example here
might be like let's say that you're
working at a video game studio and they
do the the buff overflow thing they
solve the problem some security
protection
yeah and some model as it's writing code
for and interacting with a developer it
suggests the wrong one something more
generic something that was more seen in
the real world sorry the real world but
like the generic world in the generic
World versus the the choices made in
this organization so what you might do
then is interact with model say nope
that's wrong that's not what we do we do
it this way can you change it to do it
this way then that feedback loop is
incredibly important because that piece
of data right there becomes an
incredible and it's not something you've
trained on it's not in the Corpus per se
but it's the tuning data there that
matters and that actually human
interaction with the system matters
because that becomes a very high high
value piece of data to update and say
okay you know what I can't show them
this way do it this way because this
they've already tuned me and said I need
to go this way yeah yeah that makes a
lot of sense and I guess from a quantity
perspective as you've seen these
monstrous Enterprise
codebases does it come down to 100,000
small decisions like this versus
distilling 100 big rules for new code
that is doing generated so no
Corporation in the world like we all
talk about data here in the AI side of
the fence and The Funny Dirty Little
Secret of data in the AI world we all
the exact same access to data we have
the web data the code data we're all
doing the same thing and no matter what
Corporation you are in the world or a
corporation has they can never match at
all the size of that data so what you
have to do is you have to understand how
you're going to favor client data or
customer data inside that you can never
rely on quantity of data for that so
what you what somebody would need to do
is say okay so what we're going to do is
we're going to model looks this way and
then we're going to favor some of the
interactions this way some of the the
later layers this way and then what you
then do is you have to further favor
person I would say preference data so if
you were to interact with a system and
say we this is how we want to go do that
you have to favor continue to favor that
preference yeah and then you guide those
so you're never going to have a quantity
you're never going to get to the
quantity of data next that scenario yeah
makes sense and and I guess maybe one
last question on that topic when I had
Dez on the show from intercom uh he
commented on how oftentimes at intercom
with their sort of autonomous uh AI
support agent Finn um one of the common
experiences for new customers is that
they turn it on and they realize that
Finn mimics the the knowledge base that
they have very well but the knowledge
base is bad and they have this knowledge
base and there was this informal
knowledge about what is good and what is
bad and what you should and you
shouldn't use within the knowledge base
amidst the support organization and just
never really manifested in it and it
made me wonder whether code has the same
thing which is within the
organization some things that you have
in your code you want to repeat and some
things that you have in your code you
don't want to repeat how does that how
do you deal with that challenge I think
it's as prevalent in code if not more
and in fact when we're interacting with
custom we're talking about what we do
and how we do it the most
common retort from them is but what if I
don't want my data to be favored in that
sort of way particularly like Legacy
data as an example and it's important
that Legacy data like examp be in we
make mistakes and sometimes you don't
want those repeated it's mistakes
because you had the wrong people in the
organization or just mistakes over the
time things have not matured aged well
it's always good to be able to say well
give US Representative good and bad
examples like show us so that we
understand how we can tune that system
for you it's it's just like with
anything in life you can't just go in
and just YOLO something like you know my
my my least favorite valuations of these
systems is somebody to go in and just
like point in time ask a single question
get a single response and say this is
good or bad you just can't you have to
understand each of these systems is
different and when you're interacting
with a customer it's important that you
say okay give us some of the positive
context that you want and some of the
negative and negative is the hard term
but what I mean is hey don't do it this
way or want to repeat and things you do
not want to repeat exactly we all
understand and and the code side of
Defense I think they have a lot of that
actually they have more representative
examples of these things but if they
don't have the negative side because a
lot of people don't keep the negative
examples around the positive is also
good like here's 10 modern projects that
we really want this is the style of
thing that we want to go here's all of
the data but this is the style type of
deal yeah and you can do that this is
all about customer engagement these are
not like oneclick setting systems you
have to think of these things as like
these very large kind of complex systems
yeah yeah but what do you mean Jason we
want magic we want you to come along and
just next next then it needs to work and
understand all of my system isn't that
the the promise of AI sounds there still
a little bit of expressing your
preferences involved in that process
maybe let's shift gears a little bit and
talk about the evolution of of these
code models the the general perception
amidst many people that I speak to is
that of all the domains in which llms
can improve or AI Foundation models can
improve code is is high up there because
of the ability to validate whether you
got something correct and when you
compose a poem you don't necessarily
know if that poem is correct even when
you compose an image it's hard code
offers you an opportunity in concept at
least to to for instance you can see if
it compiled right you can see but maybe
you can get a lot more detailed how do
you see this first of all is it correct
do you expect
the ability to generate codes to evolve
faster than maybe other domains and and
second is how much faster is it is it
dramatically faster or is it just hey
this will be like 10% ahead of this
other domain but all in all it's really
all about the quality of the data and
like other domains one of the core
beliefs that we have that poolside and
again I'm going to corpor speak a little
bit I'm trying not to do that it's more
of a want to talk a generic here but one
one of the reasons why we did we've done
it at poolside is we actually believe
true human level reasoning and planning
will emerge in the domain of software
first because of the some of the
luxuries that we have in software and
primarily that software is very close if
not as close as you can possibly get to
a deterministic system with a massive
Corpus of seed data so again going back
to our simulator system our
reinforcement codex back system that
allows us a set of luxuries and one of
the luxuries is generate a ton of
synthetic data that we can be unique to
us in the mod models will emerge and and
evolve better in that way but software
inherently is more bounded like it's
testable it's executable it's it's
verifiable there's a whole bunch of
things that we've not as an industry
explored yet including poola we've not
explored this we're domain specific
company and it's just we're not there
yet we will get there eventually but
could you imagine a world and marry all
of these things together marry my entire
history of canonical Heroku GitHub and
up PO side but could you imagine when
you're interacting with a system you're
asking to do something and it could
prever verify that the generation or the
code that you've done one aderes to all
your sdlc but also two is runable
executable and is running for you on a
system these are the promise and Magic
that you can have here but it's much
harder this is a harder problem to go
solve because we're talking about the
entirety of software again not just
writing a poem or an email which the
human brain is going to interpret we're
talking about these systems so it's a
harder technical problem but it's also
an easier verifiable system so that the
magic you can build around this is going
to be um pretty pretty incredible yeah
as as compared to Art I think the other
aspect of it is that there might be less
societal uh objections maybe because I
think when we talk about a lot of
definitely the Arts I don't know about
you know legal or you know drug
Discovery I guess it has its own it's
just harder to find out whether you got
it but everybody's in favor of us
getting it right so I think there's two
things here that I've personally
experienced so one is developers have
preference so you code review all of the
things right people are going to say I
don't like this style or I don't like
whatever but you can't argue with
running you can't like there's always an
old saying in software which is source
code wins so if you get into a debate at
a theoretical level typically the person
who writes this the code is going to
dominate and dictate the rest of the
conversation because everyone's reacting
to the code itself so code wins at the
end of the day and that you're going to
keep pushing that in this case here you
know people can argue all the time over
strategy differences at a legal level
like this isn't how we want to go
approach this problem
so I think there's some luxuries here uh
I also think that people are more open
no matter what we think in the moment on
Twitter about developers being lost to
AI systems people are more uh open to
advancing systems here because they're
used to everything changing every five
or 10 years no one writes configuration
files the way way they used to 10 years
ago no one does X the way they used to
five years ago so we're used to this
right so we're open to this kind of
change right as as opposed to Legal or
education or these domains that have
actually been quite stuck for quite a
while and the old Trope about developer
the lazy developer tends to win too
because they're going to automate most
of the systems and they're going to do
like this is the ultimate tool for the
lazy developer in a way and we just
remember that we like to reward people
who think creatively that way and really
use the tools as maximum their ability
instead of just having to be a human
alop 100% of the time right so this is
the perfect Segway indeed into the Maybe
Futures section of the conversation not
that we haven't spoken a ton about
Futures over here but maybe let's talk a
little bit about the person about the
developer and maybe about the sort of AI
native development reality the of the
future reality in which you are
developing software in in a way that
assumes Ai and Powerful AI is at your
fingertips so I guess the first question
I want to ask you is you referred a lot
to the notion of understanding the code
and it's my perception that when any
model analyzes code it needs to decipher
out of it all sorts of levels of
understanding about the code it needs to
understand how it operates okay how does
it move bits around and and what
operations does it do it needs to
understand what it does especially if he
wants to interact with prompts like
whatever add this ad within the checkout
process it needs to know what the
checkout process is and maybe even a
little bit of the why if it wanted to to
interact and explain things in a good
way
um so I guess what I was curious is when
I look at all the workflows that exist
today about AI assisted development it
feels like you come in with some
language that is sometimes at either of
these three levels and you make an ask
and you expect the model to understand
the code understand all of these
different facets relate it to the
request right now do all of its Voodoo
and come back with kind of proposals of
here are the changes I'm going to make
sometimes we see these sort of plans in
between and then somewhere in there
sometimes you get it right sometimes you
get it wrong you as in the model
sometimes they get it right but all of
the conclusions are only on the action
there's never really an opportunity and
we think a lot about this sort of notion
of spec Centric development or it
doesn't feel like in that process
there's ever an opportunity to critique
these layers or to have some I I think
of prompt as like interaction models
it's my ux if I clicked the button I
gave the prompt versus something that is
more long lived so and I'm sharing more
a bit this pet peeve this am I thinking
about this correctly does the model
indeed try to decipher these different
levels does it get represented should it
get represented in the future in a
better way I think this is part of the
evolution that we're going to go through
so the way that I've always thought
about these things which is and again
like the interactions that we see today
and where I think people's heads are
going to go in the future and we see um
elements of this but for the most part
you ask a model of question
what whatever it be and then you get an
output and the output is code or the
output is an answer right but it could
be code itself but you don't actually
know what steps the model went through
now you can ask the model to explain
itself but it's always a post Hawk
rational you actually want to know the
thought process and again Holy Grail we
talk about Chain of Thought we talk
about all these different types of
things but this is what we actually all
want to see these things do in the
future because we want to see that part
that part's the interesting part and if
you think about this as how you took
from the input to the output but the
middle part this is the show your work
part in school this is where all the the
points were you might have got if a
10-point question you might have gotten
two for the correct answer but it was
eight for showing your work yeah and and
that's what we need to get to we need to
get to the show your work part now what
will happen is by the time once we get
to the show your work part and everyone
builds enough trust over the show your
work part we will then start to hide the
show your work part and just trust the
output but right now we're actually
starting to ask people trust the output
without showing your work and it's a
natural thing to talk about how do I can
I trust this no there there's what you
said too is there's a lot of folks who
really want to go from like PRD hey I
want you to take a PRD I want to explain
what I want I want it in detail and then
I want to see this thing pop out the
other side of this fence we're not there
where's a long way to go from a PRD down
to here but there's intermediate steps
that we are going to need to go build
now to get to this point and that's
where we are is again we can build these
things in place now but we got to make
sure we under we as an industry I'm
using the global we here yeah don't
oversell people and and unfortunately
that will happen there will be a lot of
snake oil in this there will be a lot of
snake oil an inconsistent one as well
like things that sometimes they work
sometimes they're magical and yeah
sometimes they that's the that's
probably the more frustrating part for
folks like you and I on this who
building companies around this which is
yeah they can work po portion of the
time with a lot of glue and bailing wire
it's not going to work mostly because of
these reasons yeah which diminishes the
value of getting it right and getting
and the way I've always I tried to
describe this to folks is don't look at
a demo on Twitter don't look at a video
out there on Twitter and then say okay
I'm G to take my entire entire company
board that spaceship and go explore
space in that thing because you're just
doomed for failure that's not going to
be a thing the life support systems and
all the complex systems that are in
place there you have to make sure you
understand the inner World needed on so
so I think though back to that PRD it's
not doable today but when you think
about the developer of tomorrow
is that what they're writing do they
need to understand code once our
understanding of code and sort of the
llms got better at knowing it does a
developer still interact with a code if
not do they interact with that PRD is
yeah I've always said there's two types
of developers in the world and obviously
that's untrue because it's always more
than just two but it's easy
simplistically yeah yeah so there's two
types of developers there a developer
that wants to build an application and
everything else doesn't matter so I'm
going to solve a problem building
application I need everything else to
get out the way source code the tools
all that sort of stuff that's a thing
and a means to an end so they're not
fiddling with their neovim they're not
fiddling like they probably got a very
basic setup they just really care about
solving the problem and going off and
making money and blah blah then there's
people who love to CH to chase the stack
TRS they're they love that sort of thing
now obviously opposite EVS of the
spectrum and I'm being very generic in
distilling this down so I think in the
future you're going to see a
reinforcement on both sides of this so
the people who chase a stack Trace are
going to be giving massive amounts of
superpowers because they can further
Chase stack traces and things that they
couldn't before or do things deeper and
better and faster they're been given a
brand new set of things but those will
be will classically interact with
systems in some way with the with these
systems but the people who just want to
go build the thing they may never see
source code in the future they may get a
mid-journey style output and very likely
to be honest with you a mid-journey
style output of running software and
when something breaks they ask the
system broke how do you fix it and a
couple of different fix mechanisms are
tried until one works and then they go
and a lot of software does not like a
lot of particularly low complexity
software does not
require the type of attention that some
folks might give it over here and we
just need to be honest about that this
is not low code no code but it's an idea
behind some of these things I don't
think people are necessarily going to
always have to interact with source code
in the future yeah and I think they they
need to have an understanding of the
system I guess I I think about this a
fair bit probably touch a lot although
you're building the fundamental engine
for this as well uh which is there's the
notion of how do you produce the
software so I wrote the PRD and then
there's everything else around software
yes that is how do you version it how do
you package it how do you uh how do you
distribute it how do you roll it out
gradually which I guess gets into
operations and things like that and I
guess what what we imagine here at at
Tesla is something that that entire
development process centers around some
form of a spec or other kind of
guidelines maybe tests maybe
verifications versus revolving around
the code I think previously let's break
the world up into a couple of different
moments in time as an example June 21
when we released GitHub Copa beta
essentially or I foret what we actually
deemed it beta or Alpha I can't remember
but every line of code before that was
human endeavored and the most important
artifact was the code itself because
that was the discret unit of interaction
with these systems and since we've
entered this Dev Le AI assisted world
and where like Pandora's out of the box
type of Pandora's Box is open this thing
is is here to step at some point in the
future the source code again becomes
another art an artifact but it's no
longer the most important artifact
because it's the intentions so just like
all the software has always bed what was
this code supposed to do and so the code
itself people have always said writing
the code is interesting but reading the
code explaining the code understanding
the code is actually where a lot of
developers spend their time interacting
with these systems so I'm a Believer in
the fact that source code is still the
most important thing in the future are
we going to be able to get away with it
no I think source code is always going
to be around but developers might not
interact with the source code the same
way that I myself don't have to interact
with yl the way I had to just even five
years ago there systems that allow me to
to navigate that in ways I didn't have
to before or I couldn't sorry yeah
interact with it at a higher level
ruction yeah and either way it'll be a
very interesting Journey that's for sure
yeah and and the way i' always said this
I people ask me about Heroku actually
quite a bit because we had a grand plan
at Heroku back because back before the
acquisition post the acquisition all
that and Heroku is job not acquisition
by Salesforce for a good what 15 years
ago give or take some point yeah wow
yeah been a while we're old J but but
Heroku is effectively also job not done
it's not finished yet because Heroku
said at the highest level it was like
Hey we're going to make software
development deployment super easy get
push Heroku Master it's going to be
effing magic you're going to love this
thing but Heroku particularly as
postacquisition we'd always wanted to
start escaping hatching out because this
is what happens is 80% of the time gush
herok Master is going to be great you
never have to think about it but some
portion of the time you got to esape
hatch out and do something a little bit
more complex or bespoke or whatever and
then some portion of that time still the
Minimus more you're going have to escape
hatch out and the point is these systems
need to look like this so all of these
even AI systems we can talk about base
case and then Edge case and base case
will be like most of them are just going
to work at some point like the specs are
going to work you're going to be able to
find a certain X like spec and you're
going to be able to deploy the code from
the AI systems and you're not going to
have to think about the code but at some
point you're going to start having to
escape hatch out and do more esoteric
more complex more of a Spoke things that
they that need to support that if they
don't support that then we're in trouble
because then you're bound into a box
that you don't understand y yep and and
then I guess we don't even know what to
ask for at the moment because we're and
this is what I think developers are
going to be really doing in the future
is understanding how to ask the
questions again I don't think a
developer the future is ever going to be
able to get away from the fundamentals
of software development because they
have to be able to understand the
systems here it's the same way as you
say the hardware engineer always has to
understand the how to build these these
systems even if they're not focused on
that aspect of the system they have to
understand the basics of these things
just because yeah yeah makes sense and
we we we think a lot about a developer
either going down thead route of the
product manager as we discussed before
or going down the route of the architect
of having more more understanding of how
the moving Parts interact even if they
have less of a need to and maybe
actually to an extent they are not too
far apart from correlating to your to so
I think that's actually I've always
joked with people because I I've I've
said to myself I was a very average
developer the way my brain worked it was
the lines of code were difficult for me
to see but I could see the packages and
I could see the systems so as I
extracted myself out I got much better
at at a technical level and as a CTO was
much easier for me to be a a very good
CTO versus a very good developer as as
weird as that sounds but it's just the
way work yeah but I think that the
systems allow that sort of thing so you
can see yourself going PM or going
architect and understanding that now
there's going to be people who still
miss the lines of code and they're going
to want to write more of that themselves
but that's like somebody who wants to
hold the brush and be the artist versus
someone who's going to use mid Journey
90% of the time Y and there might be
some room for them and they might just
not be the center just this has been
fascinating I guess if people want to
track pide and and know what's coming
from it because I know you don't you're
not yet just available for them to go
off and and try it out what should they
do you follow us on Twitter at poolside
Ai and then go to the website poolside.
and sign up and we'll send that updates
perfect I'm looking forward to seeing
the Wonders that come out Jason thanks a
lot for joining us today and sharing all
the the great wisdom super super
interesting nuggets thanks guys thanks
for having me it's been fun man and
thanks everybody for tuning in and I
hope you join us for the next
one thanks for tuning in join us next
time on the AI native Dev brought to you
by Tesla
[Applause]
[Music]